Houssem Marzougui

3837 Midgard Pl, Victoria, BC, CA 778-318-7601 marzouguih86@gmail.com https://github.com/zoug86 https://github.com/usna11 in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/houssem-marzougui-0424a795

https://marzougui-h.dev

Summary – Results-driven, self-motivated and hard-working Frontend web developer with four years of work experience seeking a full-time position in an engineering and professional innovation environment which offers key participation, team-oriented tasks, immediate challenges, and career opportunity.

Professional Attributes

- Fast learner with a strong desire to master new concepts and technologies.
- Have an interest in crafting efficient and scalable modern software solutions.
- Exceptional interpersonal and collaboration skills.
- Strong capacity to work under stress and time constraint.
- Strong leadership and management background.

Skills

- HTML5, CSS3, Material UI, Bootstrap
- JavaScript (ES6)
- React.js, Next.js, Redux
- PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL,
- Node.js, Express.js, Ruby on Rails
- Jest, React libraires, Enzyme, Mocha, Chai, Cypress
- Version Control (Git), GitHub workflow, Circleci
- Heroku, Netlify, Firebase and Vercel deployment
- REST API, Postman, Docker (basic), Bash
- OOP, Data Structures and Algorithms

Education

Master of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering

2017-2020

University of Victoria

Victoria, BC, Canada

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

2007-2011

United States Naval Academy

Annapolis, MD, USA

Experience

React Developer

JAPR Technologies | Toronto, ON, Canada (Remote)

02/2022 - Present

- Developed new UI features and improved code coverage for a healthcare application (myaidin.com) that serves thousands of users daily, using React (classes and hooks based) and Redux.
- Brainstormed new automated unit and integration test strategies and consistently increased test coverage to ensure 100% quality results using Jest, React testing, and Cypress libraries.
- Contributed to backend development by actively engaging in Ruby on Rails and conducting rspec testing, reinforcing the application's comprehensive development and testing approach.

Frontend Developer

Freelance

10/2020 - 01/2022

Developed and designed several client and personal client-side static pages and full stack web applications:

 Portfolio: Personal website built with React.js and Material-Ui and features most projects built to date (all other projects should be displayed there as well).

Remote Moderator

OneClass | ♥ Toronto, ON, Canada 08/2018 – 12/2022

- Supervise and moderate platform educators to ensure highest quality service to students in North America.
- Engage undergraduate students across Canada and the U.S understand their math, computer science, and engineering learning objectives through extensive project assignments.

Technical Analyst

Deloitte | **♥** Kitchener, ON, Canada 01/2019 – 11/2019

- Produced and partially managed Scientific Research and Experimental Development (SR&ED) technical reports for clients in many industries including TMT and Manufacturing in English and French in a rapid and challenging work environment.
- Discussed and studied clients full design engineering projects to determine their innovation levels and SR&ED eligibility.

Research and Teaching Assistant

University of Victoria | ♥ Victoria, BC, Canada 09/2017 – 04/2020

 Implemented and simulated medical ultrasound imaging algorithms in Matlab using adaptive and conventional plane wave compounding techniques that reduced computational complexity and maintained similar image quality.

Software Engineer

The Naval Electronics Division | ♥ Tunis, Tunisia

- Developed a technical report and messaging application to help mechanical engineers on warships get instant feedback on different mechanical and electrical complicated issues built with JS, Node.js, Socket.io and MongoDB.
- Developed a web application that allows logistics officers instant material purchase and stock availability check built with React.js, Node.js and PostgreSQL.

Communications Officer

Tunisian Navy | ♥ Tunis, Tunisia

- Developed and supervised maintenance planning for all transmission Radio equipment onboard naval units to ensure full operational status of different communication systems.
- Developed and conducted training sessions for communication team members.

Publications

• H. Marzougui and D. Rakhmatov, "Data-Driven Sensor Array Subsampling for Plane-Wave Ultrasound Imaging," 2019 IEEE International Ultrasonics Symposium (IUS), Glasgow, United Kingdom, 2019, pp. 2337-2340, doi: 10.1109/ULTSYM.2019.8925560.

Interests

Technology, hiking, cooking, health and wellness

Languages

English (Fluent) - French (Fluent) - Arabic (Native)